<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Franco Carbonaro]]></title>
  <link href="http://francocarbonaro.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://francocarbonaro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-26T01:38:01-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://francocarbonaro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Franco Carbonaro]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tip: choosing the right provisioning profile for an enterprise application on Xcode 5 and 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://francocarbonaro.github.io/blog/2015/02/24/tip-choosing-the-right-provisioning-profile-for-an-enterprise-application-on-xcode-5-and-6/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-24T16:24:29-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://francocarbonaro.github.io/blog/2015/02/24/tip-choosing-the-right-provisioning-profile-for-an-enterprise-application-on-xcode-5-and-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since Xcode 5, I’ve been having some issues to use provisioning profiles with the same App Name ID and different bundle identifiers, this happens because Xcode just let you select the first profile that was added. That happens because Xcode identifies the provisioning based on its App Name ID, which can be identical in enterprise development, and I think the provisioning profile should be distinguished based on the bundle identifier.  To handle this situation, you will have to do as follows:  Open the provisioning profile in a text editor and copy the <string> value of the <UUID> node inside the <plist> root dictionary node. Go to Xcode > Code Signing > Provisioning Profile section and choose the Other&hellip; item, then paste the UUID here. The correct certificate can be chosen now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should I still learn Objective-C?]]></title>
    <link href="http://francocarbonaro.github.io/blog/2015/02/24/should-i-still-learn-objective-c/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-24T15:49:13-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://francocarbonaro.github.io/blog/2015/02/24/should-i-still-learn-objective-c</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been almost a year since Apple surprised everyone by introducing the Swift programming language on the WWDC. From that day on, a lot of developers wonder if they should still learn Objective-C and this is still a fair question. So, should you learn Objective-C or not? I’m going to share my opinion on this post.  Objective-C is an old language, created in the early 1980s, it’s probably older than the majority of the iOS developers, like me, who use it. It has a syntax that is definitely weird compared to other popular programming languages such as Java, PHP, C#, Ruby, etc. The syntax is so different that I know a lot of people that were discouraged to learn the language itself. In my opinion, this is more an initial shock, because after a while you’ll get used to this syntax and learn how to appreciate it.  Until last year, if you asked to an iOS or Mac developer how to learn to create an application, the first thing they would recommend you would be to learn Objective-C for sure. But nowadays some say that you could learn Swift first.  ## Career as an iOS developer If you want to be an iOS developer, the answer is pretty straightforward: Yes, you must learn Objective-C. I’m 100% sure that you’ll have some kind of contact with the language, probably by doing maintenance on an old project or by trying to watch a WWDC session video. You’ll need to be able to read and understand Objective-C in order to handle these situations.  As an iOS developer, you could work on a new enterprise project with a scope that needs to run on iOS 5 or 6, like the one that I’ve been working on for the past three years. In that case, you won’t be able to use Swift, since it is supported only from iOS 7. It’s true that this is not a common scenario, but my company has a client that bought 1,500 first generation iPads on 2010, spending almost one million USD, and for that reason they didn’t change the devices so far; that’s why I think it’s another reason to learn Objective-C.  Another case that would be useful to know Objective-C is because Swift and Objective-C are compatible, which means that you can add Objective-C libraries inside a Swift file.
 I do believe that Swift is the future for iOS development and I think that Apple focus will be to make it better, but Objective-C is a language used in thousands of projects and it won’t die so soon, so learn it.  ## If you don’t plan to be an iOS developer In this case, I would say that you could focus on Swift. There are already a lot of resources to learn the new language (Apple provided two books, for example), and a few weeks after the release, the community had already created well-crafted open source libraries like <a href="https://github.com/Alamofire/Alamofire">Alamofire</a> and <a href="https://github.com/Quick/Quick">Quick</a>.  Swift syntax follows more common patterns than Objective-C syntax and this is one aspect that will motivate more developers to create applications for iOS or Mac, or at least it won’t be a barrier like Objective-C could have been.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
